Watch Online Movies and Series for FREE
www.osdb.link/lm
Murder Investigation Team.
PS Jatri.
Received. Stand by.
Fields.
Chris.
Sorry to ruin
your evening. boss.
We just had a call
from a CHIS Handler
submitting information
relevant to Vella.
- What did they say?
- Possible suspect.
A person so far unknown
to the inquiry.
alleged to have made
a confession.
-Intels's graded the info 1
-A
on the matrix.
Okay.
Continue developing the intel.
Let's bring the suspect in.
Nice one. Right on it. boss.
Five Three. the boss
has given the go ahead
on the 2 ARVs fully crewed
with AFOs and TL
within the hour.
Sorry to call you in. sir.
Any progress since we spoke
on the phone?
We've a possible location
for the Suspect.
You okay to sign off
the Directed Surveillance
Authority?
I need a team on watch while
we pull everything together
- to raid the premises.
- How reliable is the intel?
1A from an established CHIS.
Casual sex worker.
He supplied
the Suspect's address...
Hold on. Jo.
- A rent boy?
- I don't know
if it's a commercial thing
with the CHIS
or even what his drugs
history is.
Christ sake. Jo.
he was probably off his face.
Look. just let me get
a coffee inside me first.
This is our first lead
in months.
Bloody hell. Jo.
We're good to go. boss?
Sorry. Chris. the Super's
not buying the intel.
- What?
- He needs more time.
God sake.
Stand down guys.
it's not happening.
Super's pulling the plug.
Says he wants more work
upon the intel.
- Morning.
- Morning. boss.
And don't think
I didn't notice DI Fleming
skulking in last minute
like the dirty stopout.
Don't go there. boss.
Glass houses.
All right.
Operation Lighthouse re
the unsolved murder
of Gail Vella
on September 10th. 2019.
Apologies to those of you
who were gearing up
for the op last night.
Following the Super's conflab
with the SFC.
it was decided to await
Executive Level sign-off.
The name we've been given
is Ross Turner.
Yesterday evening Turner
allegedly boasted to a CHIS
he'd been involved
in Gail's murder.
Turner's name is negative
on the PNC
and the National Database
plus local intel checks
are drawing blanks.
Hence. we're treating
"Ross Turner"
as most likely an alias.
We've been given an address.
- Flat 4 - F. Beechwood House.
In-situ surveillance
was established last night.
The team captured this image.
Enhanced here.
Turner is likely to be armed
and is considered
extremely dangerous.
Tango. Oscar. Six. Five.
TL the Hill.
Control. received. Six Five.
Mike. India. Two.
Zero. State Five.
Mike. India. Control. received.
- Did anyone see that?
- What?
- Take us round the back.
- What did you see. boss?
Take us round. Mike. India.
Two. Zero. Control.
re-routing. State Five
to possible armed robbery.
Control. Two. Zero. received.
- standing by for sit rep.
- Boss. maybe just call it in?
What the hell?
Stop at the end. no further.
See. Kate?
The van.
Mike. India. Control.
Mike. India. Three. Seven.
vehicle PNC check.
Control. Three. Seven. go ahead.
Three. Seven.
Sierra. Hotel. one. three.
Golf. Echo. Kilo.
God sake.
What the hell
are they playing at?
Control. Three. Seven.
vehicle is a red BMW
3-series. no markers.
Vehicle comes back
to a Helen Braxted.
59 Lowman Avenue.
Three Seven. received.
Let's call in backup
so we can TL.
It's only a fake plate. boss.
You know a getaway vehicle
when you see one. Kate.
Bookies right there.
Can't rule out an immediate
risk to the public.
Mike India Two Zero to TFC.
believed State 6
at Armed Robbery.
request urgent
authorisation to deploy...
Mike. India.
Control. clear to deploy.
Mike. India. Two. Zero. deploy.
Two. Zero. received.
Mike. India. Two. Zero.
Go. Six Five.
Two. Zero. received.
Mike. India. Two. Zero.
intercept vehicle.
Two. Zero. received.
Armed police!
Armed Police.
Hands on the window!
Armed police!
Out of the vehicle now!
Down on your knees!
Armed police! Drop your weapons!
- Drop your weapons!
- Armed police.
Drop your weapons!
Shit. shit. shit.
Control. Three. Seven.
active message.
Shot fired.
request urgent ambulance.
One non-police casualty.
severe GSW.
- Move them back!
- Clear the street.
I need replacement AFOs
urgently to continue operation
to arrest Vella Suspect.
repeat. urgently.
- Get down.
- Control.
- received. stand by.
- Don't move.
Shit!
Six. Five.
unarmed clear to approach.
Two Zero. received.
Let's secure the scene
and witnesses
and get this lot back
to The Hill.
Ma'am. Take witness details
and record a first account.
You okay to stay here
and take charge
while I lead the arrest
of the Vella Suspect?
Yeah. no problem. ma'am.
- Hold it.
- One. two. three.
Take them off.
Officers wearing body cams.
get in here now
and start making arrests.
Control. Mike. India.
- Two. Zero. priority message.
- Two. Zero.
Control. Two. Zero.
following firearms incident
AFO's must stand down
for forensic recovery.
Deployment of relief AFOs
will be at least one hour.
Shit!
Two. Zero. Control.
anything to speed that up
would be deeply appreciated.
Six. Five.
all AFO's remain in situ
for forensic recovery.
Six. Five. received.
Sorry. Sarge.
We've made a request
for Officer K.
To provide receipts
or equivalent
supporting his expenses claims.
It's been ten working days
and we've got nothing.
Call the Rep and say
unless they deliver.
we're moving to a Yellow Notice.
Will do.
Officer S.
She's been calling in sick.
but colleagues allege
she's been skiving off
to help run her husband's
haulage business.
I suppose we'd better start
by asking OCC Health
to request a doctor's letter.
Sarge.
Five. Three. relief ARVs are TA.
All yours. Kate.
Boss.
Two. Zero. received.
Everybody let's go.
Christ. How much time
did that cost us?
Too much.
Two. Zero State Five.
TA minus one minute.
Control. received.
Mike. India. Two. Zero.
Sierra. Lima. One. Five.
request sit rep.
Sierra. Lima.
One Five. receiving.
No change. Subject believed
still in property.
Two. Zero. received.
Mike. India. Two. Zero. Control.
TA Beechwood House.
Control. Two. Zero. received.
Mike. India.
Two. Zero. State Six.
Sierra. Lima. One. Five.
visual with ARVs.
Two. Zero Six Nine.
no further intel.
suspect is believed
to be armed and dangerous.
Six. Nine. received.
Two. Zero. Six. Nine.
Ambulance now on standby.
Over to you.
Zero.
Foxtrot. Six. Nine. received.
We're Go.
Six. Nine. going up.
Control. Six. Nine. received.
One. Five.
no movement seen in Flat 4F.
Six. Nine. received.
Two. Zero. Forensics now TA.
Control. Two. Zero. received.
Six. Nine. 4th Floor.
Control. Six. Nine. received.
One. Five.
still no obs
on subject's dwelling.
It's your call.
Two. Zero. received.
Enter the property.
Received.
Weapons free.
Armed police!
- Show yourself!
- Armed police!
Hands where we can see them!
One. Five.
they're in but still no obs.
Two. Zero. received.
awaiting sit rep.
Mike. India. Two. Zero.
require urgent sit rep.
One. Five. still no obs.
Sierra. Foxtrot. Six. Nine.
all officers secure.
One in custody.
Control. Six. Nine. received.
With me. let's go!
Two. Zero. request FC
go back-to-back on 2.
FC on 2.
They're holding the suspect
at the scene.
I need you to go up there
and get him straight
into a forensic suit for
transport to a dry cell.
Every fibre. every strand of DNA
could be crucial
in proving this is our guy.
- FC. received.
- Chris. do me a favour.
put on a suit
and get up there. pal.
Boss.
Six. Nine.
forensics clear to enter.
Five. Three. State Six.
Received. Five. Three.
Five. Three.
DP for custody transfer.
Bringing suspect out now.
Control. Five. Three. received.
Thanks for stepping in.
Totally fantastic work.
Happy to help. ma'am.
IDENT 1 was a negative
on his prints.
At first. he was reluctant
to give a name.
and then he did confirm
Ross Turner.
Sorry. Chris.
Did he volunteer the name
or was he asked
a leading question
- if Ross Turner was his name?
- Good point. Kate.
The name was put to him first.
- The ID from the CHIS...
Sorry. boss. great minds.
So. the CHIS who gave us
Turner's name and address?
We need to get him in
to confirm or deny ID
on the Suspect.
I've been on it all day. ma'am.
Handler's lost contact.
He reckons the CHIS
has bottled it.
Christ sake.
Sorry. Chris.
maybe have one more go please?
Boss.
Clearly Turner's
not what we expected.
if that's even his name.
Custody's asked the HCP
to carry out
an initial mental state
examination to make sure
he's got the capacity
to face an interview.
Not just an interview.
A person with learning
difficulties is more likely
to be the victim of crime
than the perpetrator.
You wonder
if he's got the capacity
to carry out a murder
in the first place.
There's always been
two theories.
A hit.
I agree. Kate. he's not our man.
A stalker slash obsessed fan.
That's by far
the more credible theory.
All right.
I'll get right back to you.
Sarge. Front Desk called up.
There's an officer
asking for you.
Won't say what about.
Won't even give a name.
It's late.
Fine. I'll deal with it
on my way out.
Steve Arnott.
Farida?
I'd rather not give my name.
I can appreciate why
that might be but. sorry.
if you're still at Polk Avenue.
AC-3 have jurisdiction now.
And you should contact them.
I'm on the Hill.
Murder Investigation Team.
Wait there.
Can I get you a tea
or coffee or anything?
No thanks.
The rate of unsolved crimes
is proving to be a nightmare.
But it helps the public
to realise that we don't have
the resources
to investigate burglaries.
With any luck they'll stop
reporting them.
the figures will look better.
- Ted.
- Ma'am.
Apologies. ma'am.
I just saw you booked
the conference room there.
My office must have cocked up.
I never got the invitation.
No cock-up.
Sorry. Ted. you're not
on the list this time.
I accepted the disciplinary
action. ma'am.
This matter is now closed.
You lead an anticorruption unit.
There's plenty think
you're lucky
not to have been removed.
Best keep your head down. Ted.
Got a few minutes. gaffer?
Be my guest. son. Be my guest.
Last night I took a statement
from Officer J.
Who was working
at Polk Avenue in 2017
when we investigated
DCI Roz Huntley.
Mmm-hmm.
Officer J. expressed concerns
regarding the professional
conduct of DCI Joanne Davidson.
an SIO on the Murder
Investigation Team
based at Hillside Lane.
Hillside Lane. yeah.
everybody's talking
about this breakthrough
they've made a suspect
- in custody for Vella.
- Yes. sir.
DCI Davidson was posted
to the Hill a year ago.
one month after
Gail Vella's murder.
And She took over
from the original SIO
leading the inquiry.
As you know. sir.
Gail Vella drove home late
on the evening of September 10th
in a dark grey Peugeot 108
which she parked outside
her house in Kingsgate
and was shot dead as she
got out of the vehicle.
At postmortem.
the pathologist concluded
the muzzle of the firearm
had been pressed
against the back of the skull
at the moment of discharge.
Hard-contact technique
to minimise
the spread of sound.
powder and blood.
According to Officer J.
the suspect appears to lack
the capacity
to carry out a murder
that's still unsolved
after over a year.
She also alleges DCI Davidson
unnecessarily diverted
and delayed the operation
to arrest the suspect.
And any previous criticisms
of Davidson on record?
None I've found so far. sir.
I'd like to covertly approach
current members of her team.
Wee Chloe. she's seems to be
getting on really well
out there. doesn't she.
what do you say son?
She's good. sir.
We really can't be sure
about the loyalty
of some of these people.
They could banjax
the whole thing.
Sir. regardless
of the personnel involved.
Vella's still
the highest-profile inquiry
engaging this force.
And Officer J.
Didn't go to AC-3 or AC-9.
She came to AC-12
because she believes
we'll do right by her.
She backed the right horse
there. didn't she son.
But I'm gonna need
a hell of a lot more
before I can authorise
a formal inquiry.
- Sir...
- Houl yer whisht.
I need more.
Sir.
- All right?
- Yeah.
- It's great to see you.
- You too.
I got you one. Hope that's okay.
I'm on the clock.
No. great. I appreciate you
making the time.
I should be calling you "ma'am".
Strictly speaking
but I'll let you off.
So. how can I help you. Steve?
Strictly off the record.
I've reached the end
of the line in anticorruption.
About time.
It's no disrespect
to the Gaffer.
I've stuck it out.
I'm bored. mate.
I'm ready for a new challenge.
Well. we can always
use good people.
Cheers. I appreciate it.
Sorry. I should get back.
But maybe do a drink one night?
- Um...
- Luke and I have split up.
No. it's just...
If we're gonna be
working together.
You really have been working
Anticorruption too long
ain't you.
Good to see you.
DI Fleming. MIT.
Thanks ma'am.
...number of Newspaper
and Magazine clippings
containing images of Gail Vella.
- Morning. Kate.
- Boss.
- All right. Chris.
- All right. ma'am.
I was just saying
there's a number of newspaper
and magazine cuttings
containing images of Gail Vella.
Significant.
Abundant fingerprints
and DNA deposits.
And the prints appear to relate
to two individuals only.
One of who is the suspect
we've got in custody.
Okay.
The search team detected signs
of forced entry.
Our AFOs smashed
the front door in.
The damage is
on the inside of the door.
The markings match the damage
to the back of this chair.
Any estimate
on when this alleged
- forced entry happened?
- No.
It's Farida.
Okay if I take this?
Sure.
Hey. Farida...
Possibly the chair was jammed up
against the front door to
prevent someone breaking in.
Like Chris said.
that could have happened
anytime.
Well. the place
is well maintained.
It's unlikely the damage
would have gone
unrepaired for long.
Unlikely but not impossible.
Good news.
HCP has okayed the suspect
for interview.
Great.
Have a seat.
We'll be with you the whole time
and if you get confused
by anything
it's okay to tell us.
That's just
the tape recorder starting.
it won't last long.
Murder Investigation Team
interview of Suspect A
by Detective Chief
Inspector Davidson
and Detective Sergeant Lomax
in the presence
of the Suspect's Solicitor
and Appropriate Adult.
You do not have to say anything.
It may harm your defence
if you do not mention
when questioned something
you later rely on in court.
Anything you do say
may be used in evidence.
Do you understand?
Yes.
What's your name?
If I may?
My client's informed me
that under the strain
of initial questioning
he gave the name Ross Turner.
His name is not Ross Turner.
His name is Terry Boyle.
Is that your name.
then. Terry Boyle?
For the DIR.
the Suspect is nodding.
Why did you say your name
was Ross Turner?
My client's been clear.
His name is not Ross Turner.
His name is Terry Boyle.
Okay. We'll look into that.
Moving on.
The property
where you were arrested.
- Flat 4 - F. Beechwood House.
Is that where you live?
Do you live in the property
or were you just visiting?
- No.
- No. you don't live there
or no you weren't visiting?
Mr Boyle has provided me
with his address.
He does not reside
at Beechwood House.
He resides
in the Kingsgate area.
Flat B. Dorton Villas.
Okay. we'll look
into that as well.
Interestingly.
the Kingsgate area
is where a journalist called
Gail Vella lived.
Do you know
who I'm talking about?
Suspect nodded.
Thank you.
For the DIR.
I'm showing the suspect
item reference RCG-6.
RCG-6 is a press cutting
featuring an image
of Gail Vella.
I'm also showing the suspect
item reference RCG-7.
another press cutting
featuring an image
of Gail Vella.
and item reference RCG-8.
also a press cutting
featuring an image
of Gail Vella.
Do you recognise
these press cuttings?
For the DIR. the suspect
is not responding.
Do you recognise this woman?
For the DIR.
the suspect is nodding.
What's your relationship
to this woman?
Nice lady.
Suspect answered. nice lady.
MIT have put the IDs
of the Armed Robbers
up on the database.
Have a look at this.
- This it?
- Exactly.
Between them these guys
have never robbed
anything bigger
than their local Greggs.
And they just happen
to be on the exact route
and time of an op
to bring in a suspect
in an unsolved murder.
Based on Officer J.'s statement.
the MIT convoy
was travelling up hill.
past this parade of shops.
Well. where's the bookies?
It's around the corner.
It's already
a narrow line of sight.
You add in Davidson's convoy
travelling at high speed.
I'll call in for the footage
off the security camera.
You go and check out
the camera in the bookies.
Sarge.
DI Fleming. MIT.
visiting Terry Boyle's flat.
- Ma'am.
- Thanks.
Hi. any updates.
So far. apart
from the pics on the walls.
we're not finding much
evidence of this
being anyone's
permanent residence
let alone the suspect's.
The place is clean.
Extremely clean.
Ta.
So. the suspect's
alleged address
contained even more
Gail Vella images.
And neighbours positively
ID'd his picture.
Meanwhile we've interviewed
a number of residents
at Beechwood House.
Whoever lived in Flat F
kept himself to himself.
And the few
that did notice a resident
describe him
as dark-haired and stocky.
Like Terry Boyle.
What we really need
is the CHIS to confirm
whether Terry Boyle
was the man that confessed
to an involvement
in Gail Vella's murder.
or it was someone else entirely.
Tell me about it.
My patience is all used up.
Set up an urgent meet
with the CHIS's Handler.
Cheers. Boss.
Boss.
this is the CHIS's Handler.
I've brought him up
to speed on our inquiry.
DS Marks.
DCI Davidson.
You'll have heard from Kate
how important it is for us
to acquire your CHIS's intel.
I'm doing everything I can.
I don't know
what more you expect.
For a start you could help us
locate your CHIS.
I've been trying
to make contact with him.
He's gone to ground.
Then no disrespect. mate.
but we've got the resources
to find him.
You're asking me to disclose
his identity?
You know I can't do that.
Is the word "ma'am"
in your vocabulary?
To locate your CHIS
and convey him
to a place of safety from which
he can assist our inquiry.
we need you to disclose
his identity.
No.
Ma'am.
Are you worried about him?
Yes. Of course. I am!
I'm sorry Sarge.
You've reached PS Farida Jatri.
Please leave a message.
Farida. it's Steve Arnott.
Look. we're progressing
the inquiry.
but I need your help
to fill in some of the gaps.
Call me when you can. okay?
Thank you.
MIT. DI Fleming.
Thanks for calling me
back Sarge.
How do you spell that?
Jo.
Sir.
The Chief Constable's been on.
I said I'll call back
with an update.
Too early to say. sir.
I should have been back home
ages ago. my feet up.
Have you got our man or not?
Like I said. sir.
too early to say.
We'll need another
twelve hours with him.
Ah for God's sake.
We've hit a bit
of a brick wall. sir.
The CHIS.
he's dropped off the radar.
If this is going to go
the way we want.
we need to find out who he is.
We've got a job to do.
The Handler's
within his rights not to.
Fuck the Handler.
And fuck the CHIS.
Okay. Any chance you
could scan over the paperwork?
Suspect's been bedded down
for a rest period.
Not much more happening tonight.
I might leave soon.
I was thinking the same.
No worries
you've been a big help.
Okay. Thanks. Bye.
Sorry. boss.
What's up?
I've taken reports
from the Surveillance Teams
in situ at Beechwood House
where Terry Boyle was arrested.
When we were diverted
to the Armed Robbery.
there was some confusion
over the Surveillance Authority.
What confusion?
Well. the team was only in place
under Directed Authority.
and it got queried
as requiring Intrusive Authority
because they were using
extreme high-power lenses
to view inside the property.
Shit.
Yeah. Which means they had to
pull out until it was sorted.
Looks like the Super
messed up the paperwork.
How long was Beechwood House
not under surveillance?
Three and a half hours.
Which means...
we don't know if Terry Boyle
is this person
or this person was able
to flee the property
during the absence
of surveillance.
I see.
We'll have to factor that
into our thinking.
I haven't shared this
with anyone else. boss.
Thanks. Kate.
Someone comes
from Anticorruption
you worry they're not
going to be a team player.
I got fed up of nicking coppers.
I'd rather go after the psycho
that murdered Gail.
Cheers. boss.
What have we got?
Based on the claims
made by Officer J.
DCI Davidson ordered the convoy
to attend the armed robbery
on the grounds
there was an urgent threat
to the public.
Fair enough.
This is the Getaway Van
that triggered
DCI Davidson's suspicions.
And these are the MIT vehicles
passing through at high speed.
This. according to Officer J..
is the moment Davidson
made her decision.
But that convoy
was going like the clappers.
You'd do well to spot
a pipe band in there.
I agree. sir. that's why
we need more evidence.
But you have an informant
on the team. right.
She's not responded
to any of my efforts
to make further contact.
Gonna need more. son.
Kate's Davidson's Deputy SIO.
If anyone's got
the inside track. it's her.
I am aware.
No one's better qualified
or better positioned
to act as a CHIS or even a UCO.
I'll give it some thought.
Carry on.
Sir.
Boss. Ma'am.
Pathologist says
he died instantly.
The pattern of injuries
implies a fall from height.
Okay. have we confirmed ID yet?
I took the liberty of sending
a photo to the Handler.
He confirms it's the CHIS.
Shit.
Sorry. boss.
Got the file on the CHIS.
Low-level offender
named Alastair Oldroyd.
Unfortunately.
there's nothing on CCTV
so whatever happened to him.
happened in a blind spot.
Door-to-door haven't found
any witnesses to the fall.
Right.
A number of people
do report hearing a scream.
Suggests he was pushed.
but not conclusively.
Either way.
we've lost the only person
that can say for certain
if Terry Boyle claimed
to have been involved
in Gail's murder
or it was someone else.
Yep.
If only we'd have been
given his ID.
we might have been able
to have saved him.
Exactly.
Cheers boss.
Steve Arnott.
Farida. are you okay?
What's happened?
Our most important witness
was just found dead.
What witness?
This is too dangerous.
Wait.
you're not suggesting
Davidson was involved?
You have no idea
what she's capable of.
none at all.
Don't call me again.
Second MIT interview
of Terry Boyle
by DCI Davidson and DS Lomax.
Mr Boyle.
you remain under caution.
Please refer to Document 36
submitted in Disclosure.
Document 36 is a report
regarding fingerprints
-detected at Flat 4
-F
Beechwood House
during a lawful search
on 27th October.
A number of said prints
match the fingerprints
obtained from Mr Boyle
following his arrest.
A significant number
of other fingerprints
match an individual identified
by the Police National Computer
as Carl Banks.
Terry. what is your relationship
with Carl Banks?
Do you know Carl Banks?
No comment.
You sure that's how
you want to answer?
Can you tell us
who is Carl Banks?
I suggest you arrest Mr Banks
and put that question to him
rather than to my client.
So far we've been unable
to trace Carl Banks.
Perhaps your client
will provide information
that will help us locate him.
For the DIR.
the suspect is not responding.
Document 42 submitted
in Disclosure.
For the DIR. Document 42
is a report
on chemical traces detected
in Flat B Dorton Villas
on 28th of October.
Said traces have been
identified as cleaning fluids.
Did you carry out a thorough
cleaning of the premises
in order to destroy
forensic evidence?
For the DIR.
the suspect is not responding.
Image 27 submitted
for Disclosure.
Image 27 is a crime scene
photograph
captured during a lawful search
of Flat B Dorton Villas
on 28th of October
showing the kitchen area.
Markings on the floor
suggest a large appliance
had been present for some time.
Please cross-reference
with Document 42:
chemical traces detected
resembling refrigerator coolant.
Our assumption is the removal
of a refrigerator or freezer.
What happened to this appliance?
I don't know.
Document 42 again.
Further chemical traces
were detected
which have been identified
as two substances
listed under the Misuse
of Drugs Act in Class A:
cocaine and diamorphine.
Diamorphine is
commonly known as "heroin".
Have you ever used
these substances?
Do you have an explanation
for why these substances
were detected in your flat?
No comment.
These are powerful substances.
Even in small quantities.
they can affect mood and memory.
They can cause unpredictable.
violent behaviour.
Images 20 to 22.
Images 20 to 22
are photos of Gail Vella
found in Flat B Dorton Villas
during a lawful search
on 28th of October.
Document 44 submitted in...
May I interject?
You've presented evidence
of intense cleaning
at my client's home.
Why. then. would these
incriminating images
have been left behind?
Document 44 submitted
in Disclosure.
Document 44 describes
deposits of semen
detected on said images
of Gail Vella.
Analysis of these deposits
of semen
gives a 99.9% probability
that they originated
from your client.
Did you want to have sexual
relations with Gail Vella?
Did you want her
to be your girlfriend?
For the DIR.
the suspect is not responding.
Did you become angry
or frustrated?
Did it make you want
to hurt Gail?
For the DIR.
the suspect is not responding.
I'm showing the suspect
an image of an article
of clothing. BC-9. recovered
from Flat B Dorton Villas
on 28th of October.
Document 60 submitted
in Disclosure.
Document 60 is a report
of particles of gunshot residue
detected on BC-9.
Mr Boyle.
did you shoot Gail Vella?
What kind of nobby signal
was that?
First thing that came to mind.
Go round the block.
in case anyone's watching.
No worries.
There's a nice little balti
up the road
but I'm guessing that's not
why you're here though.
I wish. Sorry. mate.
Right.
I can't share any details.
but we might be looking
into Vella.
Oh shit.
Great. so when Buckells
and Davidson find out
- they're gonna think...
- They'll think either
you're our CHIS or you've
been embedded as a UCO.
That's why I'm giving you
a heads-up. Kate.
Steve. you know what it's like
being ex-anticorruption.
I've had to work my bollocks
off for them lot.
Is this the Gaffer's way
of getting his own back?
No. of course not.
Why am I still
calling him Gaffer?
He knows why you moved on.
Yeah. that's what worries me.
AC-12 was tainted when
the Gaffer got investigated.
Look. you've done your time.
made DI.
You wanted to move on.
He knows
it was nothing personal.
Except you stayed.
So what next?
You opening an official inquiry?
We can keep it on the DL
only if we've got a CHIS
inside MIT.
Great. So either
I'm accused of being a traitor
or I become one
to avoid being accused?
Jesus Christ. Steve.
I'm gonna have to think
about it.
Cheers. Kate.
and that's all anyone can ask.
The address
where Terry Boyle was arrested
was covered in prints
matching Carl Banks.
One initial line
of inquiry in Vella
was a contract killing.
According to my informant
on the Hill.
Operation Lighthouse
has detected forensic evidence
linking to this suspect.
Carl Banks.
Carl Banks has an extensive
history of violence
including firearms offences
and a long association
with organised crime.
It's much more likely
to be the gunman
than the local oddball.
That's for sure.
Yes. sir. It would appear
that if DCI Davidson
deliberately delayed
the operation
to arrest the suspect.
it's possible
this was instrumental
in enabling Banks.
the real killer. to flee.
If we want to get to the
truth. there's no choice. sir.
we've got to start formally
investigating Davidson.
Well. that's what we do. son.
We hunt the truth.
Inquiry authorised.
Thank you. sir.
What are you waiting on.
a puff of white smoke?
Sir.
I thought we agreed
you'd be out?
You don't even want to talk
about it?
We've talked enough.
I just want to get the last
of my things.
I don't want a row. Farida.
It's over.
Farida. Please.
You moving in with her now?
"Her"?
Smart money's on Kate Fleming.
Kate and I have been shagging
on the sly for months
even though she's straight
and I never cheated on you.
Now I see why
you never made detective.
Don't patronise me!
You think you're so fantastic!
You think you're so powerful!
No. but at work I'm your boss.
and I've still treated you
with respect
the whole time you've
destroyed our relationship
- with your paranoia.
- And out of work.
what am I to you?
You still act
like we're just friends.
- You're ashamed of me!
- No. of course not.
How come I've never met
your family?
I don't have one.
You're lying!
Everyone has a family!
This is why I'm leaving.
This madness.
I'm sorry. Jo.
I'm sorry.
I love you. Jo.
Please don't go.
Jo. he made a confession.
It's not good enough. sir.
No. this isn't good enough.
This isn't good enough.
This is your gig. Jo.
Christ sake!
I can see
you're frustrated. sir.
Oh. really? Really?
Thanks for that!
Thanks a million!
We need to consider next steps.
Look. what am I
gonna tell the Chief?
I've explained everything
clearly. sir.
Would you like me to go
through it again?
Boss? You okay?
I just took the Super
through my decision
on Terry Boyle.
I've recommended he be put
on police bail pending
further inquiries.
I've released him
without charge.
Right.
Don't look so surprised. Kate.
I wasn't born yesterday.
The gun...
The gunshot particles
aren't enough without spatter
of Gail Vella's blood
or tissues.
And the CHIS. Carl Banks.
Terry Boyle's flat.
Something doesn't add up.
Yeah. I agree. boss.
I just want to catch the
bastard who killed Gail Vella.
She's what this is all about.
No way am I going after
someone like Terry Boyle.
because he's the easy way out.
Boss.
is everything okay?
Thanks. Kate.
- I should. uh...
- Yeah.
The police
need to know where you are
at all times. and your flat's
still a crime scene.
so they've arranged for you
to stay in what they call
Approved Premises.
You'll be safe there. Terry.
Thank you.
>>>>oakislandtk
www.opensubtitles.org
Watch Online Movies and Series for FREE
www.osdb.link/lm